[insects buzzing]
You,
you have always found me.
So please,
from now on, I'm asking you,
be the light again
that guides me.
[♪ opening music begins]
[♪ opening music ends]
Today at Omiyo Ohashi
Bridge, an incident
occurred resulting
in a section-
What happened?
Guess the bridge is
out for the time being.
That's so scary!
Oh, I see.
So you saw Lisa?
[LARA] Lady Witch, why does
my big sister have legs?
Well, why else? It's because
she took my potion.
-But why?
-How should I know?
She just took it from me
without even asking.
It was a real nuisance.
So you have an older sister?
[sighs]
I will not allow a mermaid
and a human to fall in love.
Why, big sis?
The fish swimming energetically
above you here are
called sweetfish.
The fish swimming down at eye
level are carp and crucian carp.
Today I'd like to tell you about
the different kinds of fish
you can find in Lake Biwa.
[GIRL] Wow, so pretty!
-That there is a Biwa trout.
-You mean as in Lake Biwa?
You're right, that's
where it's from,
but someday it'll go back to
the river where it was born.
They're called anadromous fish.
That's right, very impressive.
[LISA] So?
[KOTA] It's a dead end.
No matter where I searched, I
couldn't find anything special
Right.
It's been over 100 years
since the witch vanished,
so I think it's highly likely
that she's no longer
here at Lake Biwa.
How's your injury since then?
I'm fine.
It's just-—
[gasps]
Lara, you have to understand.
We're running out of time.
[LARA] So you see, about that,
that was something
that Father gave to me.
1783 A.D.
And I was so happy.
Lara! Come on, hurry up!
[grunts]
[Lara giggles] I got him!
[cries out]
[LARA] I was so surprised.
His mouth is really huge.
Don't you think that's cute?
Hey, Lisa, you really like
that fish, don't you?
I mean, because you're
always together.
Yeah, he's really funny.
No matter where I am,
he always finds me.
He finds you?
He's a mysterious fish
with only his eyes
sticking out of the sand.
He once found a beautiful cave
filled with colorful minerals.
He was able to find this
very spot that we're
playing in today.
I reckon with that
light, he can find
anything in the world from
even the darkest corners.
Look! He found me again!
[LARA] Oh!
You're right, he found you!
[both giggle]
Hey there!
Sorry for screaming.
[ROWAN] Lara was a truly
special princess to us all.
However, after being betrayed
by those hideous humans, Lara-—
It can't be!
There is no longer
a princess who is
able to bring light
to this castle.
[ominous sound]
So the castle will
soon crumble.
We must abandon our
home and spend the rest
of our lives Searching
for somewhere new.
[GRACE] What a situation!
[Lisa gasps]
[LARA] What?
It's her.
The witch.
It's Grace.
[GRACE] You pitiful
castle folk.
I do hope you're
not too distraught.
In place of that useless
king of yours, Rowan,
I myself will lead you to
new seas and a new home.
Follow me.
Unless you want to
die, that is.
Where will you take us?
[GRACE] To the mansion
I built myself.
Why? Why would we go with you?
Because your king
asked me to take you.
If there's another safe
place you know of,
then please go right ahead.
[Grace laughs maniacally]
[Lisa screams]
[ocean waves fade]
[MAN] Look, it moved!
It's alive!
[gasps]
[MAN] Is this real?
[pants]
[MAN] Oh, it's so creepy.
[LISA] Stay away!
[MAN] What's this?
- Oh.
- No!
Give it back!
[gasps]
Let me go!
Help!
[screams]
[box shuts]
[indistinct chatter]
Ladies and gentlemen, amazing
birds from faraway lands!
Give them a round of applause
for their lovely songs!
[audience applauds]
All right, next up,
prepare to meet a mythical
creature of the deep.
Now be careful not to be
deceived by her alluring eyes.
Ladies and gentlemen, I
present the mermaid!
[gasps]
[♪ soft piano music]
[audience applauds]
Let me out of here!
Let me out!
I need to get out of here!
Hey!
[gasps]
[♪ soft piano music continues]
Ladies and gentlemen,
roll up and see for yourselves!
Proof that anything
is possible!
Truly the catch of the century!
Show your appreciation with
your cheers and money!
[♪ soft piano music continues]
[audience cheers]
The mermaid!
Let me out.
I hate this place.
It's so dark, I can't see.
[♪ tense music]
[♪ soft piano music]
[crowd screaming]
[gasping]
[low growling]
[grunting]
[intense growling]
[♪ piano music intensifies]
[gasps]
[♪ piano music ends]
[glass shattering]
Is it you?
You should know. After all,
I will always find you.
[♪ melancholic music]
Sorry I couldn't get there
right away to get you out.
What happened to you?
I took the witch's potion.
[Lisa gasps] Oh no.
[KOTA] As long as you're safe,
nothing else matters.
[LISA] Why go to such lengths?
You always used
to compliment me
on being
very good at finding you, Lisa.
Remember?
Although it was you, you were
the one who found me first.
You saved me.
That made me happier
than anything else.
What will you do now?
I know that my role ends here.
You should go back,
join everyone else.
Lady Lisa!
No, don't!
What are you doing?
Why?
You found me when I was alone
and lost in the darkness.
So in that case, from now on...
will you please be the
light that guides me?
[♪ guitar strumming]
- [KOTA] Lady Lisa!
-[LISA] I'm okay.
[KOTA] Have some potion.
Right, let's turn back today.
No, we'll keep going.
To the place where Father
and the others went.
[LISA] Finally, we've made it.
1931 A.D. OKISHIMA
[underwater sounds]
Father!
[fast footsteps approaching]
[ROWAN] Lisa, that... form.
Why, my daughter?
Why do you have
those hideous legs?
This place...
[ROWAN] This is the lair
of that accursed witch.
After a long journey,
we arrived here having lost
almost all of our light.
Now, Lisa, listen close.
Just over there,
Lara is sleeping.
- [LISA] Lara!
- She had turned to foam,
but I have bestowed light
upon her once more
in the hope that
Lara might reclaim it.
The light of the castle.
The light that only the
princess possesses
is what
we need.
I want to restore the
glory of my castle
and my loving
family once again.
Lisa, in my absence, you must
wait for Lara's resurrection.
Lady Lisa!
[gasps]
[LISA] The door, it won't open!
Humans are such
inconvenient creatures.
The witch!
How pathetic, the way they run
away as if scared by water.
Leave this place!
We will protect everybody here
until Lara eventually wakes up.
Oh, do be quiet.
Rowan just wanted to
sleep like everyone else.
You've deceived not only Lara,
but also my Father
and my family.
I won't dignify that
with an answer.
Once my potion runs out,
you two will vanish into foam.
This is a sacred place.
Return to the surface, humans.
KOTA MINASE
- [KOTA] Kota?
-That's what I've chosen.
That's your name from now on.
[KOTA] Okay. I will follow you
wherever you go.
[LISA] Just as the witch said,
that potion
is about to run out.
So before we turn to
foam and vanish,
we have to get our
hands on that potion.
And I will do anything
to make sure that happens.
SEIZO HORIKOSHI
KYOTO CHUO UNIVERSITY
[MAN] Hmm, what's this?
[LISA] This is...
something that will
change your life.
[magical sound]
To have to rely on the
hands of those despicable
humans is abhorrent.
However, seeing as this
potion is forbidden for us
and it must be
acceptable for humans,
it was a gamble worth taking.
[magical sound]
[MAN] I was captivated by
the brilliant light that
this mysterious potion held.
I have dreamed of
such a medicine
which unlocks infinite
possibilities for life.
[LISA] The structure
of human knowledge
differs vastly from that
of the mermaid world,
hypothesis and verifications.
However, the more we understood
it, the more we realized
that recreating the potion
would be no easy fit.
[MAN] It seemed to
contain life itself,
as though the Star of Life
dwelt within it.
Days passed, and we continued
to pursue this special light.
[magic sound]
It was as though it
were invisible to us.
[LISA] Just what is the
true nature of this light?
[MAN] I couldn't understand
where the light came from
in the first place.
I need to know...
I have to know the essence
of this radiant life.
However, it...
[BOTH] seems that-—
[LISA] I have unfortunately
run out of time.
HORIKOSHI FAMILY GRAVE
Human words are so
unnecessarily exaggerated,
embellishing their own
short lives like this.
Such a waste of time.
[KOTA] He spent his entire
life creating this,
and all we have is
this poor imitation.
But regardless of that, even
though it's not the real thing,
it seems to delay
the process a little.
Yeah.
1984 A.D.
[clock ticking]
THE NATURE OF LAKE BIWA
AND THE HISTORY OF ITS BIOLOGY
[clock keeps ticking]
VISITING PROFESSOR LISA SHIOMI
[LISA] Lara still hasn't
come back to life.
Even this fake potion is
beginning to lose its potency.
2026 A.D.
[KOTA] The survey of lake Biwa
will conclude very soon.
If I could find the witch,
the potion would surely-—
[both gasp]
Lady Lisa, you were right!
[LISA] Lara, please,
find it for us.
Find it soon.
[KOTA] Lady Lara's fine, but
she has human legs.
[LISA] Listen, Lara, a mermaid
and a human,
there's absolutely no way
they can love each other.
But... things might be
different tomorrow.
[gasps]
Lara, that wonderful
light of yours,
why won't you choose
to shine it on us?
AND NOW...
[gasps]
[breathing heavily]
[phone ringing]
LISA
[continues breathing heavily]
[gasps]
[phone ringing]
[Lisa panting]
[panting]
[gasps]
[♪ melancholic piano music]
[crying]
Lady Lisa!
[sighs]
[Lisa grunts]
I know you must be
showing symptoms as well.
[sighs]
It won't be long until this
doesn't work anymore.
[KOTA] But, if only...
if only we had Lady
Lara's special power.
[magical sound]
Lady Lisa?
[♪ fast flute music]
[gasps]
-[KOTA] Wasn't that...?
-[LISA] The witch.
No way!
She's been watching us
all along?
That's it, I found her.
She's been in the house.
The whole time.
[♪ closing music begins]
TRANSLATION:
SACHIKO TAKAHASHI
TIMING: ANDY ELLIS
EDITING AND TYPESETTING:
ASHLEY BARBOZA
QUALITY CONTROL:
RILEY DALTON
TRANSLATION CHECK:
SRIRAM GURUNATHAN
[♪ closing music ends]
[street noise]
One time, me and my brother got
into a fight.
We didn't talk for a month.
Hmm.
My big sister once said-—
[clatters]
[♪ soft breeze and harp music]
[gasps]
[♪ music intensifies]
[magical sound]
Ah!
[♪ orchestral music]
[grunts]
TO BE CONTINUED